MATHIAS DALMAS



Villa Mercedes, San Luis | (C) +54 2923445561 |

dalmasmathias@gmail.com

Summary

An engineer with extensive experience in Procurement (8 years) and Production (1.5 years). Currently, I work as a Supply Planning Supervisor at Mondelēz International at Villa Mercedes plant, where I lead a team of 4 people in material and production planning. Previously, I worked as a Sourcing Specialist with a focus on Latin America (Mexico, Perú, Brazil & Argentina). Before that, I held positions at Toyota Motors as an Ssr Buyer and at Arcor Saic as a production engineer. I am a responsible, punctual, and productive professional, prepared to embrace new challenges that will further enhance my career.

Summary of qualification

- · Act as a troubleshooter
- Figure out practical ways to get things done, overcoming obstacles in the way
- Remain calm during crises and thus have a settling effect on others
- · Ability to adapt to challenging and changing environments

Work History

Supply Planning Supervisor - Mondelēz International (Jan 2023 – now)

- Planning the short and long-term supply chain from source to destination for both internally and externally produced items, for review and approval.
- Leading, training, and developing a team.
- Meeting KPIs including achieving or exceeding customer fill rate, providing finished goods inventory at or below targets, and achieving set waste reduction goals.
- Working closely with internal and external departments such as manufacturing, marketing, sales, materials, and replenishment to achieve category objectives.
- Ensuring performance based on approved detailed and master schedules, long-range plans (including capacity considerations), and material requirements plans using system tools.
- Supporting and implementing improvements within the planning scope to enhance customer fill rate, inventory targets, and waste reduction to meet company KPIs.

Sourcing Specialist - Mondelēz International (March 2020 – Dec -2022)

- Sourcing strategy deployment
- Prepare and lead required regional bids and supports global negotiations processes if needed.
- Identify opportunities to improve the productivity pipeline agenda in short and long term.
- Work close with R&D/ ISC and Finance to build collaborative model in order to support KPI improvements VMI / DIOH/ DPO. Develop and guarantee 100% GSFI certificated suppliers
- Price contracts in SAP updated timeline process in order to guarantee source in quantity and time.

Sr Buyer – Tubhier SA

(Feb 2019 - Mar 2020)

- Local procurement representative in plant (the other part of the team was in commercial offices in Buenos Aires)
- Alignment of purchasing strategies with Production Director
- Ensure goods delivery in order to ensure production continuity
- Align with stakeholders goods' standardization.
- Develop local supplier.

Ssr Buyer - Toyota Motors

(April 2014 – Dec 2017)

- Price Negotiation of Plastic Autoparts
- Achieve cost reduction activity plan
- Ensure delivery on time & quality requirements
- Leadership on Die Graining project for new models. Ensure delivery leadtime, line up organization spectation with suppliers. Ensure quality excellence and delivery on time.
- Cost Breakdown analysis
- Leadership in volume increment project from Purchasing division side.

Production Engineer – ARCOR Saic

(Oct 2012 - Apr 2014)

- Leader of production shift in 3 shift of 8 hours.
- Supervision of a 20 people team
- Scrap improvement (97% of scrap declared, 10% improvement in scrap reduction)
- Ensure production availability ensure lines fill.
- Standardization: Implement standard in main production lines

Education

Data Science with Python (Jan 2023 - today)

IBM certification

Chemical Engineer (2006 – 2011)

Universidad Nacional del Sur – AR

Languages

English – Proficient Portuguese – Avanzado

Courses

"International Buyer Training" by Toyota North America (Michigan, EEUU)